<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Experience Design &amp; Media Strategy
</description>
    <link>http://uncommonplaces.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://uncommonplaces.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 15:06:57 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 15:06:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Designing Sex, Death, and Survival in the 21st Century</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/156004893?color=2C691A&amp;amp;title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of creating transgressive adventures that transform people’s sense of risk and possibility in urban environments, I’m now bombarded by requests from onlookers who want in. They send eager emails asking how they can be added to the list as if selling themselves to me will gain them admission to some secret society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each request breaks my heart a little. I would love for more folks to make their own daring rituals of transgression and transformation. Why are they waiting for me to do it for them? This question has sent me on a quest to distill what exactly makes an intimate social experience truly transformative. By mashing up game design and the anthropology of ritual, I think I’ve figured out what some of the key elements are. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful experience designers, self-identified or not, tend to employ similar strategies, especially when it comes to opening people up to risk in a caring way. I’ve been going on adventures with avant-garde morticians, sex party purveyors, and seasoned wilderness guides to understand how they bring people into intimate contact with challenging situations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://designresearch.sva.edu/&quot;&gt;The Design Research Program&lt;/a&gt; at the School of Visual Arts has gotten me started. &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/contact.html&quot;&gt;Sign up for updates&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#105;&amp;#100;&amp;#097;&amp;#064;&amp;#117;&amp;#110;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&amp;#109;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#112;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you’d like to be part of the next steps. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://uncommonplaces.com/2016/04/sex-death-survival/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uncommonplaces.com/2016/04/sex-death-survival/</guid>
        
        <category>Reflections</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2015 Year in Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve now finished my first &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saturn_return&quot;&gt;Saturn return&lt;/a&gt;. (I don’t believe in astrology but can’t help getting into it). All the illusions of what adulthood would be have fallen away. The discomfort of perpetual challenge and uncertainty is starting to feel exciting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of people are telling me that I seem to be doing great on a purely energetic level. Something about my vibe is much more grounded and engaged than previous years. It’s delightful to be told this spontaneously on a regular basis. Something’s working in my favor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(See previous reviews: &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/2015/04/2014-year-review/&quot;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/01/2013-year-review/&quot;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016/soa7517.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crew Party&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-laundry-list-of-what-i-did-in-2015&quot;&gt;The Laundry List of What I Did in 2015&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Sextantworks&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://sextant.works/&quot;&gt;sextant.works&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orchestrated an intrepid overseas &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/yDgwtgLLnj/&quot;&gt;private&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/ySgTLMQ1Iz&quot;&gt;commission&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ran a big, wild, crazy domestic private commission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hosted a &lt;a href=&quot;http://sextant.works/lab.php&quot;&gt;Placemaking Lab on Governors Island&lt;/a&gt; in NYC &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ran &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/TimCon31?src=hash&quot;&gt;TimCon31&lt;/a&gt; (4th year now, here’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://sextant.works/timcon&quot;&gt;the first one&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lead a little undercover adventure at &lt;a href=&quot;http://futureofstorytelling.org/&quot;&gt;FoST&lt;/a&gt; (again)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got certified as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/2015/08/wilderness-emt/&quot;&gt;Wilderness EMT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gave a public presentation for the Awesome Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consulted here and there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Other Professional Endevors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Studying for an &lt;a href=&quot;http://designresearch.sva.edu/program/&quot;&gt;MA in Design Research&lt;/a&gt; at the School of Visual Arts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spoke @ the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tribecafilminstitute.org/events/detail/tfi_interactive_2015&quot;&gt;Tribeca Film Festival&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spoke @ &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/2015/08/flux-harbor/&quot;&gt;Flux Factory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advised the &lt;a href=&quot;http://magnumfoundation.org/photoex/&quot;&gt;Photography, Expanded&lt;/a&gt; program at the Magnum Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nudged &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io/&quot;&gt;the School for Poetic Computation&lt;/a&gt; along as a member of the advisory board&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quietly guided &lt;a href=&quot;http://theheartradio.org/&quot;&gt;The Heart Radio&lt;/a&gt;, where I am also on the advisory board&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Redid this &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/2015/04/move-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Misc. Personal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feeling more connected with family&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally renewed my long expired learner’s permit (Yes, this feels like an accomplishment.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got my first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/4dDwDctH_r/&quot;&gt;tattoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;themes-of-the-year&quot;&gt;Themes of The Year&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The insights below are culled from my weekly and monthly reviews over the course of the year. I have 4 years of written weekly and monthly reviews at this point. It’s uncanny to watch myself change by reading the structured relections. I highly recommend picking up this pracitce. It might help you imagine yourself changing in the future, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/dan_gilbert_you_are_always_changing&quot;&gt;a curiously hard things to do&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;settling-into-my-intuition&quot;&gt;1. Settling into My Intuition&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building on &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/04/2014-year-review/&quot;&gt;my intentions last year&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve been following my intuition, maybe too much! The shame and tension of doing what my gut says has more or less fallen away. A few years ago, I read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://happinesshypothesis.com/&quot;&gt;Happiness Hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;, which does a lovely job of describing a view of the mind as an elephant and a rider. The elephant is the huge and powerful unconscious. The rider is the conscious, and the rider and elephant working together can really go places. My intuition is the elephant, and now that I have spent some time letting the elephant run the show, it’s time to get the rider and elephant more in sync. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;steering-a-big-ship&quot;&gt;2. Steering A Big Ship&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last year saw me carrying the weight of substantial responsibilities, including the biggest projects I’ve ever led by a magnitude of 10. In the past, I felt like I was on a fun and at times nauseating roller coaster called life. Now, it feels like I am steering a damn big ship (my elephant???) and mostly keeping us on course despite the storm. This is partly evident in my shorter laundry list of things I did, amounting to fewer things on a larger scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cant-control-other-people&quot;&gt;3. Can’t Control Other People&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my biggest fails on projects had to do with relationships that went sour. I was dogged about bringing things to a happy conclusion, but that can only happen when all parties play ball. I can’t force an amicable resolution, especially when the other party has needs and expectations that are beyond my ability to address, and even more so when they don’t accept that it’s beyond my ability to address them. I can’t force a happy ending for everyone in these cases.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lost-in-the-weeds&quot;&gt;4. Lost in the Weeds&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s weird reading through weekly and monthly reviews to find insights I had, smart knowledge about situations and people, that I proceeded to ignore when I got deeper into the situation. It’s like my naivete overran my wisdom, or my intellectual beliefs about the world caused me to deny what I knew about what was going on. I was not great at doing monthly and quarterly reviews this past year. I wonder if the gap in higher level perspective let me get lost in the weeds periodically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;no-more-suffering-in-failure&quot;&gt;5. No More Suffering In Failure&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m finding greater satisfaction in diving in and surrendering to something with full attention and drive, not necessarily knowing how things will turn out because of it. Rather than hedging my bets to play it safe, I’m mustering the courage to go all in. There is greater pain along the way with this approach, but choosing the pain of complete engagement over the numbness of not fully trying has its benefits. No more judging myself for failure if I know I gave it my all. Judging myself for not having done things in my power is far more devastating. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the couple of quarterly reviews that I did complete, I remarked on lingering remorse in the wake of old optimism about things that didn’t pan out. Optimism is a setup for disappointment if the visions of success is not predicated on one’s efforts and actions now. Turns out a more fulfilling optimism can be found in wholehearted engagement, in current effort and presentness. It requires maintaining a vibrant vision of success while sustaining enough skepticism about it happening to give it your all at every step of the way. It’s a curious mental trick to sustain balanced optimism and skepticism for full engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://uncommonplaces.com/2016/01/2015-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uncommonplaces.com/2016/01/2015-review/</guid>
        
        <category>Reflections</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Flux Thursday Talk - NYC Water</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was invited by Maddie Hewitt to participate in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fluxfactory.org/events/august-flux-thursday/&quot;&gt;Flux Factory talk on NYC Water&lt;/a&gt;. After researching the harbor for the past year and a half, I had some simple observations to share about one of the biggest overlooked spaces of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/harbor/14-08-21NavyYardDryDocks033sm.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-open-space-in-nyc&quot;&gt;Best open space in NYC&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York harbor is one of the largest natural harbors in the world, and it feels like almost no one out there. May times I was out on the water with dense skylines and not another boat in sight. The harbor offers a sense of openness like nowhere else in the city.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nowhere-to-park&quot;&gt;Nowhere to park&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berthing (or docking) a boat is a deceptively complex task. The berth needs to be the right shape and material for the given vessel, spots need to be available to secure the right kind of lines, the water needs to be deep enough, and you need to be able to get on and off the boat safely. Then, on top of this, you need permission to be there and services such as electricity, running water, and waste disposal options. In a city once geared toward the waterfront, options of berthing boats are now few and far between, often coming at a steep rental price. No wonder no one is out on the water anymore.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;oldest-regulations-in-the-city&quot;&gt;Oldest regulations in the city&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the excuse the coastguard gave us for all sorts of activities being complicated to pull off. New York was founded and populated by water. Movement of people and goods by water was one of the first things to be regulated. The layers of rules and agencies gets into a complexity that I only brushed up against over the course of the year, so I can’t speak to it in detail. But the combination of old regulations combined with comparatively minimal usage and traffic today make for a high friction environment for getting things done.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;historic-boat-people-are-dedicated&quot;&gt;Historic boat people are dedicated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the berthing and regulations challenges, it’s nearly a miracle that historic boat operators keep their operations going. Folks like David Sharps of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://waterfrontmuseum.org/&quot;&gt;Lehigh Valley Barge&lt;/a&gt; and Mary Habstritt of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lilacpreservationproject.org/&quot;&gt;Lilac Lighthouse Tender&lt;/a&gt; run passion projects of keeping these ships accessible to the public despite what seems like every possible natural and bureaucratic and financial obstacle to do so.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lighthouses-are-in-limbo&quot;&gt;Lighthouses are in limbo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of those quiet shifts in the build environment that captures my imagination so is changes in lighthouse administration. Gone are the days when a person needed to live at a lighthouse year round to keep the light burning. Now the lights are automated and solar powered. Coast guard simply has to check up on them every few weeks. This leaves the houses and towers of lighthouses available for re-purposing. The government &lt;a href=&quot;http://disposal.gsa.gov/LighthouseProgram&quot;&gt;has been auctioning them off at bargain rates&lt;/a&gt; since 2008. Takes include the independently wealthy to the dedicated cultural institution to wide-eyed entrepreneurs to dubious New York mob affiliates. Many more lighthouses are up for sale. It will be interesting to see how they are re-purposed.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;islands-hold-dirty-secrets&quot;&gt;Islands hold dirty secrets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each beautiful, maintained, polished island in NYC, there is a forgotten, neglected island of dubious history. These islands are the psychological underbelly of a city that has grown and shifted through multiple historical periods and shifting populations. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hoffman_Island&quot;&gt;Hoffman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swinburne_Island&quot;&gt;Swinburne Islands&lt;/a&gt; were created to dump off immigrants too sick for even Ellis Island. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_and_South_Brother_Islands&quot;&gt;North Brother&lt;/a&gt; similarly rots away as former home to institutions for the sick and unwanted. Roosevelt Island is currently getting remade, with the various hospitals being removed for modern academic institutions. Still in dark times are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hartisland.net/&quot;&gt;Hart Island&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/07/14/nyregion/rikers-study-finds-prisoners-injured-by-employees.html&quot;&gt;Riker’s Islands&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/harbor/14-08-06FortWadsworth001sm.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://uncommonplaces.com/2015/08/flux-harbor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uncommonplaces.com/2015/08/flux-harbor/</guid>
        
        <category>Reflections</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wilderness EMT</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning things the hard way seems to be my M.O. of late. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nols.edu/wmi/courses/wemt.shtml&quot;&gt;Wilderness EMT&lt;/a&gt; course by NOLS WMI kicked my ass. I haven’t taken a science class or studied for a standardized test since high school. After bombing the first quiz, I had to do a major turn around on my study habits to keep up. The pace was unrelenting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-wilderness-emt&quot;&gt;Why Wilderness EMT?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the course so that &lt;a href=&quot;http://sextant.works/&quot;&gt;Sextantworks&lt;/a&gt; can continue be responsible in executing experiences. We have some great medical people who join us regularly, but it’s a different thing to have the core members of the team fully trained and thinking about safety from the get go. Given what we have pulled off already, we’re only getting more ambitious. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course covers everything that a regular urban Emergency Medical Technician training does plus variations and practice for administering care when you don’t have access to more advanced medical support. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nols.edu/&quot;&gt;The National Outdoor Leadership School&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nols.edu/wmi/&quot;&gt;Wilderness Medical Institute&lt;/a&gt; have sterling reputations for their rigor and integrity. I seemed to be the least versed in NOLS culture among the students. Everyone else there glowed with respect and admiration for the organization. After going through the WEMT program, I can see why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT329cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT207cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-we-studied&quot;&gt;What We Studied&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to classroom time, we practiced hands on practical skills, outdoor scenarios, and did emergency room rotations in local hospitals. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;patient-assessment&quot;&gt;Patient Assessment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core skill is the patient assessment system, a series of steps to determine the condition of a patient. Breathing, circulation, and consciousness are the big picture components to life, and checking those out first offers signs to underlying issues. Obvious bloody, painful traumas might not actually be the biggest life threat in an accident. Following the patient assessment system increases the likelihood that you will catch life threats immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT151cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT228cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;


&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;practical-skills&quot;&gt;Practical Skills&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You wouldn’t think that putting a splint on someone would be so hard, but there are plenty of ways to do it wrong. We practiced skills like splinting, administering oxygen, and CPR until they sunk in on the muscle memory level. By the end of the course, I could backboard a patient in under 5 minutes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT101cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT128cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;


&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT212cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT123cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;scenarios&quot;&gt;Scenarios&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scenarios ranged from one patient / one rescuer situations on the lawn outside the classroom to whole class endeavors in the woods at night. Problem-solving a traumatic injury was curiously stressful if the patient was in pain or passed out, even though we knew they were pretending. Acting as a patient was as insightful as acting as a rescuer because you experience what good and bad treatment feels like. In the more involved scenarios, being a patient could be scary and disorienting. I felt empathy for patients in real world traumatic situations, which will make me a better rescuer in the future. The game designer in me recognized these scenarios as light weight live-action role-playing. I wonder if pushing the role-playing would add to the educational experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT056cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT349cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;


&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT070cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT201cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;emergency-room&quot;&gt;Emergency Room&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergency room environment was alternately boring and enthralling. Either nothing was happening or there was a flurry. Helping with real medical emergencies burned those particular issues indelibly into my brain. I prepped a man with a gangrenous foot for amputation, watched a woman have a transient ischemic attack, and helped a doctor insert a chest tube into a man with tension pneumothorax. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;leadership&quot;&gt;Leadership&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leadership skills were not an overt part of the course, but they were expertly modeled by our instructors. Tate, Daniel, and Atila worked together seamlessly, delivering a wealth of expertise and support while still putting enough fear of God in us so we excel. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;happy-ending&quot;&gt;Happy Ending&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I passed both the course and the national EMT exam. I am a certified Wilderness EMT! Here’s to ever more enriching and responsible endangerment together through &lt;a href=&quot;http://sextant.works/&quot;&gt;Sextantworks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wemt/15-07WEMT331cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All photos by Tate Higgins.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://uncommonplaces.com/2015/08/wilderness-emt/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uncommonplaces.com/2015/08/wilderness-emt/</guid>
        
        <category>Reflections</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Move to Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I learned to develop for the internet because of &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;. In the past 6 years, I made over 20 custom WordPress sites for my own projects and for clients. It’s easy to start with small edits on available themes, move to making themes from scratch and later mess with plugins. As my development skills got better, I no longer needed a full blown content management system (CMS) like WordPress to present my own projects online. I bypassed Wordpress to just write vanilla HTML, CSS, and PHP. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/wordpress.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/jekyll.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;time-for-a-change&quot;&gt;Time for A Change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until recently, my portfolio site was a bloated, clumsy implementation of WordPress. I used it as a testing ground for too many new technologies, from JavaScript plugins I didn’t fully understand to a content distribution network (CDN), which worked fine but was unnecessary for a small site with minimal traffic like mine. The design and some of the content were out of date as well. I design the site to attract freelance work in web development and event production. Now I do most of my projects through &lt;a href=&quot;http://sextant.works/&quot;&gt;Sextanworks&lt;/a&gt;. My personal portfolio site needed to serve a new function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was ready for something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io/&quot;&gt;SFPC&lt;/a&gt;, where I teach and sit on the steering committee, moved its site to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFPC/sfpc.github.io&quot;&gt;Casey and Zach developed the site&lt;/a&gt;, and it was an interesting process to watch. Jekyll is a static site generator. A static site generator is like a CMS in that the content, structure, and style of a site are in separate files. They differ in that the static site generator compiles the website on your local development environment before it’s published to a web host. No need for a server to assemble a page each time it’s requested.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to give it a try. In a weekend, I completely redesigned my site and ported the WordPress content over to Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
The Old Site
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/2015-03-21_OldPortfolioSite_BlogPost.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
The New Site (You&#39;re looking at it!)
&lt;img class=&quot;block-th&quot; src=&quot;/images//2015/2015-03-21_NewWebsite_BlogPost.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sifting through countless blog posts and tutorials, here are the Jekyll resources that I can recommend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Podcast: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewebahead.net/54&quot;&gt;The Web Ahead Episode 54&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;An hour long conversation about where static site generators sit in the evolution of the web, including commentary from the people who build the healthcare.gov site on Jekyll. Start here for context on what static site generators are and what it means to work on a large scale project with one.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Screencast: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pluralsight.com/courses/static-websites-with-jekyll&quot;&gt;Static Websites with Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is the only substantive screencast I could find on building sites in Jekyll. It’s an hour long and covers all the basics.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Official Stuff: &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home/&quot;&gt;The Jekyll documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Helpful blog post with instruction on migration: &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.girliemac.com/blog/2013/12/27/wordpress-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;How-to: Migrating Blog from WordPress to Jekyll and Host on Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://red-team-design.com/moving-from-wordpress-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Moving from WordPress to Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.8thcolor.com/en/2014/05/migrate-from-wordpress/&quot;&gt;From Wordpress to Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-process&quot;&gt;The Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I did to move my site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Followed instructions in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.girliemac.com/blog/2013/12/27/wordpress-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; to export comments to Disqus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exported content out of WordPress with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/jekyll-exporter/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Exporter Wordpress Plugin&lt;/a&gt; (This produced much better results than doing a standard export from WordPress and using the Jekyll WordPress importer.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/quickstart/&quot;&gt;Downloaded Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and dropped the exported content into a fresh installation of Jekyll. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed legacy WordpPress code, especially blog posts with image styling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coded out the design with the help of &lt;a href=&quot;http://foundation.zurb.com/&quot;&gt;Zurb Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. I was hoping to use Grunt while developing the site. I’ve used CodeKit and look forward to dropping, a but the version of Foundation that I used doesn’t support it. As I code, two terminal windows run ‘compass watch’ and ‘jekyll serve’. Easy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Publish! Any Jekyll site can be hosted with a custom URL for free on GitHub, but I have been deploying most of my repos with &lt;a href=&quot;http://beanstalkapp.com/&quot;&gt;Beanstalk&lt;/a&gt;, so I just stuck with that workflow. Much like my relationship to WordPress, maybe I’m a good enough developer now to move off of beanstalk and start deploying with Capistrano or some other option that works with GitHub. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-results&quot;&gt;The Results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My website is way fast. Way, way faster. Others have seen &lt;a href=&quot;http://euri.ca/2012/wordpress-vs-jekylloctopress-speed-test/index.html&quot;&gt;great speed improvements&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Editing markdown and serving a Jekyll site is a great compromise between coding out the sites with just HTML, CSS, and PHP and using a CMS like WordPress. I’m enjoying the best of both worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will I keep using Wordpress? Yes, but specific purposes that suit client needs and encompass more involved functionality. WordPress is a powerful open source project with a lot of history, a knowledgeable community, and tons of resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, a shift is in play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sites that I would have custom designed for clients on WordPress 3 or 4 years ago are being created on hosted services like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Squarespace&quot;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; by would-be clients themselves today. Developers who would use WordPress to host their own simple sites because it was the best option are moving to static site generators in droves. How we create, organize, and host content online will soon look nothing like the content management systems that have been evolving over the past decade. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wrote this blog post at the 2015 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.writespeakcode.com/&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;Write/Speak/Code&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt; conference, and amazing organization empowering women software developers to become thought leaders.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://uncommonplaces.com/2015/04/move-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uncommonplaces.com/2015/04/move-to-jekyll/</guid>
        
        <category>Reflections</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2014 Year in Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve avoided writing this post for a month and a half now. I did my yearly review on time, right around the beginning of January. The verdict: 2014 was tough. It dragged and gnawed at me in subtle, frustrating ways. Looking through my weekly and monthly reviews was painful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was there a major catastrophe in 2014? No. Did things near and dear to me come crashing down? Not exactly. So what made the year (and my review) so painful? Groundwork was done for things that will take some time to bear fruit, I confronted personal hurdles, and I disengaged from ingrained ways of thinking that were holding me back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/01/2013-year-review/&quot;&gt;last year’s review&lt;/a&gt;, this one successfully silenced that nagging voice inside of me that says I haven’t done enough. I know why I ended the year exhausted and frustrated, and I can claim my accomplishments, as subtle as they may be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015/Wanderlust-SchoolOfSellingOut-19sm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Govenors Island Residency&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-laundry-list-of-what-i-did-in-2014&quot;&gt;The Laundry List of What I Did in 2014&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Sextantworks&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://sextant.works/&quot;&gt;sextant.works&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Re-branded from “Wanderlust Projects” to “Sextantworks” in response to a cease and desist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orchestrated &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/06/wanderlust-borscht-belt-kutchers/&quot;&gt;The Mambo&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gothamist.com/2014/05/21/kutshers_photos.php&quot;&gt;last grand Borscht Belt resort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Threw another great &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/TimCon30?src=hash&quot;&gt;Timothy Convention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Redesigned the pledge for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://keepachildalive.org/black-ball/&quot;&gt;Alicia Keys Black Ball&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did a little thing at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://596acres.org/donate/gala/&quot;&gt;596 Acres Gala&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Held a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/12/28/nyregion/they-say-art-is-dead-in-new-york-theyre-wrong.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;pop up speakeasy&lt;/a&gt; for our friends because we don’t do enough things for our friends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organized the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sextant.works/sso/sellingout.php&quot;&gt;School of Selling Out&lt;/a&gt; at Kickstarter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made a good showing at &lt;a href=&quot;http://futureofstorytelling.org/summit/&quot;&gt;the Future of Storytelling&lt;/a&gt; for a 2nd year in a row&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consulted here and there&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orchestrated a few experiences as private commissions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got tons of great press: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/12/28/nyregion/they-say-art-is-dead-in-new-york-theyre-wrong.html&quot;&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/event/music/320741516/on-a-magical-mystery-tour-with-hassan-hakmoun&quot;&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/3031330/innovation-agents/this-companys-business-plan-includes-trespassing&quot;&gt;Fast Company&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://oglobo.globo.com/cultura/uma-noite-transformadora-em-sao-paulo-13981220&quot;&gt;O Globo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/05/21/heres-what-happens-when-n_n_5319604.html&quot;&gt;The Huffington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Other Professional Endeavors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Left my game company &lt;a href=&quot;http://playistheantidote.com/&quot;&gt;Antidote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did a &lt;a href=&quot;http://micro-un.org/&quot;&gt;residency on Governors Island&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advised the &lt;a href=&quot;http://magnumfoundation.org/photoex/&quot;&gt;Photography, Expanded&lt;/a&gt; program at the Magnum Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Judged the &lt;a href=&quot;http://designingforfreespeech.org/&quot;&gt;Teatrum Mundi Design for Free Speech Competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Judged the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macktez.com/stipend/&quot;&gt;Macktez Summer Stipend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organized a few &lt;a href=&quot;http://yellowthreadsociety.org/&quot;&gt;Yellow Thread Society&lt;/a&gt; get-togethers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/06/school-poetic-computation/&quot;&gt;Attended&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io/&quot;&gt;the School for Poetic Computation&lt;/a&gt; in the Spring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sfpc.hackpad.com/collection/rzM5ub4vZWm&quot;&gt;Taught at the School for Poetic Computation&lt;/a&gt; in the Fall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Misc. Personal &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overhauled my personal archive and reference system, going paperless with full OCR and a research database&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did significant apartment renovations, including a bathtub installation and loft bed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changed up services I’d been using for year that weren’t cutting it anymore, including my web hosting provider, my bank, and my cell service&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kept up with my newly established exercise routine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Settled into a regular meditation practice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did typing and speed reading drills for several months to correct for dyslexia issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-was-so-tough&quot;&gt;What Was So Tough?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;leaving-the-first-company-i-started&quot;&gt;1. Leaving The First Company I Started&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting &lt;a href=&quot;http://playistheantidote.com/&quot;&gt;Antidote Games&lt;/a&gt; with Mohini Dutta and Ben Norskov was a delightful and empowering career move. We studied game design in school at Parsons. As students, we worked on a few projects for major humanitarian organizations. The demand for our work continued. Our little design studio / consultancy was born. Sextantworks grew alongside Antidote in a similarly organic fashion. After a while, it was hard to maintain my involvement in both in any satisfactory way. I knew that Ben &amp;amp; Mohini could carry on without me. I’m proud of the foundational work I did to get Antidote off the ground. I miss being involved in game design projects and social impact work, but I love focusing on Sextantworks wholeheartedly and moving people in profound ways through experience design.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;following-my-intuition&quot;&gt;2. Following My Intuition&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My close friends and colleagues will attest to the dyanmite advice I give when they are most lost. Their glowing feedback has convinced me to take my intuition more seriously. It is rare that setting aside other’s expectations to follow my intuition produces bad results. Very, very rare. My written weekly reviews give me a window into this process as it plays out over months. 2013 was the first year I could &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/01/2013-year-review/&quot;&gt;see this irrefutably&lt;/a&gt;, so I followed my intuition even more in 2014. I chose not to meet people’s expectations in the immediate in favor of long term results, to both my benefit and theirs. Behaving this way kicked up a lot of shame. No wonder I hadn’t done it more in the past! The demons of low self-worth snarled in my ears as I bore the weight of other’s confusion, frustration, and dismissal. I couldn’t have stuck it out if I didn’t have a meditation practice and an exercise routine. It’s going to be easier in the future, but holly wow was the psychic drag on following my intuition fierce this year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;home-renovations-are-not-my-strong-suit&quot;&gt;3. Home Renovations Are Not My Strong Suit&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Yorkers periodically go through the hell of leaving one apartment for another. The process is inherently traumatic for all but the most privileged and lucky. I am incredibly grateful to be able to stay put in the same place for 7 years running. Even better that I can build out funny lofts and install salvaged bathroom fixtures. But I proved to be terrible at physical build out on an ambitious home renovation project. Maybe I was scarred growing up from too many insane home improvements instigated by my flamboyantly DIY parents. As soon as the apartment became a the construction zone, my mind was mush. I didn’t see the challenge coming, and I couldn’t follow through on much of the envisioned work. I’ve learned my lesson. A happy ending is in sight. My 2014 was very much hindered in the process, though. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-about-the-good-parts&quot;&gt;What About The Good Parts?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-school-for-poetic-computation&quot;&gt;1. The School for Poetic Computation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/01/2013-year-review/&quot;&gt;2013 year in review&lt;/a&gt;, I pointed out how I wasn’t programming as much as I’d liked. Attending &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io/&quot;&gt;the School For Poetic Computation&lt;/a&gt; fixed that. You can read about my experience there in &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/06/school-poetic-computation/&quot;&gt;an earlier blog post&lt;/a&gt;. I was thrilled to be invited back as part of the team going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;social-graces-ftw&quot;&gt;2. Social Graces FTW&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years of working with the charismatic and charming N.D. Austin are starting to rub off. I’m learning to keep my natural grumpy snob in check. Kindness, warmth, and encouragement are emotional tools at my disposal more than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-glit-filter&quot;&gt;3. The G.L.I.T. Filter&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the inspiration of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sextant.works/sso/sellingout.php&quot;&gt;School of Selling Out&lt;/a&gt;, Sextantworks has pinpointed the qualities that make a project a good fit. They are generosity, location, intimacy, and transgression (aka G.L.I.T.). We size up opportunities faster and more exactingly now that we have distilled the qualities down to a handy acronym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to a more rewarding and peaceful 2015!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://uncommonplaces.com/2015/04/2014-year-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uncommonplaces.com/2015/04/2014-year-review/</guid>
        
        <category>News &amp;amp; Updates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Birthday Surprises</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend is full of birthday surprises. I’m helping orchestrate two. For my own birthday this year, I was treated to a surprise from some people very dear to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks in advance, I received this card in the mail:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-3658 size-full&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/09/20140717_091553.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20140717_091553&quot; width=&quot;2288&quot; height=&quot;2906&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Cute acronym in the sign off.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed the instructions and dutifully told no one, not even those I suspected of organizing it, that I had received the invitation. Sitting on the secret was incredibly delicious. At the rendezvous point on the given day, I was handed a suitcase and another envelope with instructions to go to Penn Station and board a train with the enclosed tickets. I still didn’t know where I was going. Apparently there was an envelop in the suitcase that would explain everything, but I was not to open that until I was on the train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My destination was a Zen Buddhist monastery in the Catskills. I was to stay for 4 nights. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bluecliffmonastery.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Blue Cliff Monestary&lt;/a&gt; felt like a world away with all the mindful eating and working while the monks and nuns chattered in Vietnamese. It’s an outpost of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Th%C3%ADch_Nh%E1%BA%A5t_H%E1%BA%A1nh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/a&gt;’s order. I have been meditating nearly every morning since the fall of 2013 and often lament that I just want to be left alone for a whole day at a time, which seems impossible in New York City. Sending me to Blue Cliff was a very thoughtful gift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically enough, and unbeknownst to my kind birthday conspirators, Blue Cliff is a defunct &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Borscht_Belt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Borscht Belt Resort&lt;/a&gt;. The loquacious taxi driver who took me from the train station to the monestary said it was called Jeronimos back in the day. A lot of performers stayed there because it was quieter than the big resorts. Having &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/06/wanderlust-borscht-belt-kutchers/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;soaked up Borscht Belt history&lt;/a&gt; to orchestrate Wanderlust’s experience &lt;a href=&quot;http://wanderlustprojects.com/themambo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“The Mambo”&lt;/a&gt;, I took to educating all the other sutra-toting attendees about the place’s past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3660 size-full&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/09/20140721_122556.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The major lodging on the property dating at least to the 1970s was condemned. The monks and nuns, either out of economic lack or Buddhist acceptance, had no plans to fix it up.&quot; width=&quot;4128&quot; height=&quot;2322&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    The major lodging on the property dating at least to the 1970s was condemned. The monks and nuns, either out of economic lack or Buddhist acceptance, had no plans to fix it up.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3661 size-full&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/09/20140721_121754.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The swimming pool had been converted into a vegetable garden. This is the shallow end. If you look closely, you can see the 2 foot marker.&quot; width=&quot;4128&quot; height=&quot;2322&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    The swimming pool had been converted into a vegetable garden. This is the shallow end. If you look closely, you can see the 2 foot marker.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2014/09/20140721_123015.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The central dining hall and offices sported a classic 1960s style glass-enclosed stare case that I had seen at Kutcher’s Country Club as well as Penn Hills, where Wanderlust orchestrated our first illicit experience.&quot; width=&quot;4128&quot; height=&quot;2322&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    The central dining hall and offices sported a classic 1960s style glass-enclosed stare case that I had seen at Kutcher’s Country Club as well as Penn Hills, where Wanderlust orchestrated our first illicit experience.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The daily activities were less structured than you might expect from a Zen center. I was often at a loss of what to do with myself. Between sitting in meditation and silent meals, I read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Quiet-Power-Introverts-World-Talking/dp/0307352153&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking” by Susan Cain&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Transformation-Healing-Sutra-Establishments-Mindfulness-ebook/dp/B006JO1SKM/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Transformation and Healing” by Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/a&gt;, an interpretation of the sutra on the four establishments of mindfulness. By day 3, everything I did felt like some sort of meditation. Mindfulness was contagious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The birthday interventions I’m helping with this weekend weren’t hard to put together, but you have to wonder when your life will tip over into doing nothing but surprises for your favorite people. The danger seems quite real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the closing paragraph of “Transformation and Healing”, Thich Nhat Hanh shares his take on the risk and reward of perpetual birthday joy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Those who practice mindful living will inevitably transform themselves and their way of life. They will live a more simple life and will have more time to enjoy themselves, their friends, and their natural environment. They will have more time to offer joy to others and to alleviate their suffering. And when the time comes, they will die in peace. They will know that to die is to begin anew or just to continue with another form of life. When we live out life this way, every day is a Happy Birthday, a Happy Continuation Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/09/birthday-surprises/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/09/birthday-surprises/</guid>
        
        <category>Reflections</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wanderlust Projects in Fast Company</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/3031330/innovation-agents/this-companys-business-plan-includes-trespassing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fast Company&lt;/a&gt; calls us “Innovation Agents.” In the video interview, N.D. and I talk about risk, discovery, and getting past boundaries. Check it out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/embed/2fc63950659bd?rel=1&amp;amp;src=embed&amp;amp;veggiemode=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/07/wanderlust-projects-fast-company/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/07/wanderlust-projects-fast-company/</guid>
        
        <category>press</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The School For Poetic Computation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the original story of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Ugly_Duckling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“The Ugly Duckling”&lt;/a&gt;, there’s a moment where the despondent and rejected fluff ball sees a flock of migrating swans overhead. He recognizes them as his people, a group where he will no longer be the teased and abused outsider. The ugly duckling is too small to join the migration and waits out the cold winter until he is fully grown and the flock returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you been through a lonely winter like that–where you knew who you’d be at home with, but for reasons outside your control, you weren’t ready to join in yet?**&lt;br /&gt;
**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3605&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-3605&quot; alt=&quot;Via https://flickr.com/people/omp_production/&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/06/5110651248_691a4beae8_b.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Via &lt;a href=&quot;https://flickr.com/people/omp_production/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;OMP Productions&lt;/a&gt; on Flickr
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the ugly duckling who just has to wait and grow a little, joining the creative flocks I so admire requires deliberate trial and error. I saw one of those flocks pass over head sometime in undergrad, when I did half of my BFA work in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newschool.edu/parsons/bfa-design-technology/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Parsons’ Design &amp;amp; Technology program.&lt;/a&gt; It was a struggle to keep pace with my more technically savvy classmates. I saw work that inspired me greatly. I learned that interactive and computational technology could gracefully accomplish what I awkwardly manipulated documentary photography to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been years of cold, lonely winter where I applied the experience and interaction design skills I learned in the Design and Technology program to &lt;a href=&quot;http://wanderlustprojects.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;physical&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://playistheantidote.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;analogue&lt;/a&gt; settings, but I struggled to acquire the technical prowess I craved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;winter-thawed-the-flock-returned&quot;&gt;Winter Thawed, the Flock Returned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that flock was &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the School For Poetic Computation&lt;/a&gt;. This past Spring, I was very happy to find myself with the heap of &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io/people/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;beautiful swans&lt;/a&gt; at the SFPC (or would it be a stack?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3595&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-3595&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration by Taeyoon Choi&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/06/learning.png&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Illustration by &lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Taeyoon Choi&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SFPC describes itself as school for artists taught by artists. Not everyone attending was an artist strictly, but everyone optimistically embraced creative expression through computation as a means and an end. The school ran on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFPC&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open source code&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFPC/finance-and-administration&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open finances&lt;/a&gt;, and to a large extent &lt;a href=&quot;https://sfpc.hackpad.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an open curriculum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3599&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-3599&quot; alt=&quot;Getting a Raspberry Pi up and running with Jonathan Dahan&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/06/Sunday_morning_Raspberry_Pi_workshop__sfpc_school.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Getting a Raspberry Pi up and running with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathan.is/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jonathan Dahan&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SFPC can’t teach you to be better at technical execution, much like learning to write poetry won’t improve your punctuation or grammar. SFPC can’t position you for a career in any direct and obvious way. And as far as I can tell it probably can’t fix shoddy thinking, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io/mission/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SFPC Mission Statement&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is not a program to get a degree, there are large programs for that. This is not a program to go for vocational skills, there are programs for that. This is a program for self initiated learners who want to explore new possibilities. This is a program for thinkers in search of a community to realize greater dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What SFPC can do is deepen your appreciation of computation as an expressive medium, get you engaged with a community of practitioners, and leave you with a host of new possibilities to explore. You gain a deep appreciation of the potential of code to do profound and beautiful things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3609&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-3609&quot; alt=&quot;Becky Stern and her Adafruit creations. &quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/06/Loving_the_electronic_embroidery___sfpc_school__bekathwia.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://sternlab.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Becky Stern&lt;/a&gt; shares her &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adafruit.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Adafruit&lt;/a&gt; creations
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My opening presentation was on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/idaimages/sfpc-intro-lightingtalk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tenements and the borscht belt&lt;/a&gt;. My closing presentation was about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/idaimages/ida-sfp-cfinaltalknonotes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;my mom’s domestic textile arts practice&lt;/a&gt;. It was all fine and welcome. I’m not sure what other technology intensive would look at these contributions and see a swan at work rather than an ugly duckling. And how did my presentations relate to what I actually worked on during the two weeks? Let’s just say it was all pretty poetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3596&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-3596&quot; alt=&quot;Opening presentations at SFPC.&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/06/sfpc_school_opening_presentations.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Opening presentations at SFPC
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-sfpc-in-particular-is-awesome&quot;&gt;Why SFPC in Particular is Awesome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;radical-transparency-in-finances&quot;&gt;Radical Transparency in Finances&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This goes along with the artist school mentality. Expensive education on endeavors of unclear practical application and material benefit is inherently an exclusive pursuit of the privileged. SFPC aims to be accessible while being realistic about what it takes materially and financially to create a supportive community of practitioners. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SFPC/finance-and-administration&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Commitment to radical transparency in finances&lt;/a&gt; ensures an ongoing, rigorous engagement with how to do this. Artists and money–&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@omershapira/nobody-goes-to-art-school-to-make-money-so-fuck-off-48fee12e24c2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sometimes it’s just not about the money&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;everyone-was-there-for-the-right-reasons&quot;&gt;Everyone Was There For The Right Reasons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The openness, curiosity and supportive disposition of the cohort bowled me over. It shows clarity in messaging on the part of SFPC (or just the right opacity) and a great screening process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;packed-schedule-yet-a-flexible-approach-to-learning&quot;&gt;Packed Schedule, Yet a Flexible Approach to Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was always lots of brainpower in the room, between the core staff, the guest lectures, and the cohort of participants. The planned schedule gave us tons to work on and be inspired by, but there was also a spaciousness about what the group gravitated toward and needed. What was taught very much responded to the group’s momentum. The brainpower available meant that specialized workshops could happen on the fly. If you didn’t know what to work on at any one moment, there was bound to be something going on or someone who could use a hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3600&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-3600&quot; alt=&quot;Controller gloves created in Kaho Abe&#39;s workshop&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/06/My_very_own_diy_glove_controllers__Thanks__kahodesu___sfpc_school.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Controller gloves created in &lt;a href=&quot;http://kahoabe.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kaho Abe&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s workshop
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-the-program-did-for-me&quot;&gt;What the Program Did For Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having toiled mostly alone to learn tech stills for the past few years, it was incredibly comforting to arrive at SFPC and realize the extent of what I had accomplished. It’s easy to underestimate what you know when it’s just you and the whole contents of the internet to judge yourself against. The concepts I managed to master on my own were fairly simple, like nested for loops and version control systems, but in a social context where the background and expertise of the participants varies widely, it was impossible to second guess the utility of what I had taught myself. I gained a lot of confidence to simply keep it up. It’s hard to think you’re doing something wrong when &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesystemis.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Zack Lieberman&lt;/a&gt; is searching Stack Overflow to answer your questions and testing some of the same possibilities you did (albeit much more quickly and elegantly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3597&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-3597&quot; alt=&quot;Zach Lieberman demonstrates bit planes. &quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/06/The_bitplanes_of__zachlieberman.__sfpc_school.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesystemis.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Zach Lieberman&lt;/a&gt; demonstrates bit planes
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a host of new tools and concepts to play with. I would never have expected that I would spend as much time mucking around with Python as I did, for example. It was also incredibly fun to get my first Raspberry Pi working and play around with routers and mesh networking. I have a laundry list of fresh reading and tinkering to do that will fuel my creativity for some time to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3601&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-3601&quot; alt=&quot;My router served me up a drink recipe when I got it working in a workshop with Sean McIntyre&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/06/My_router_just_served_me_up_a_cocktail_recipe.__sfpc_school.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    My router served me up a drink recipe in a workshop with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boxysean.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sean McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3602&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-3602&quot; alt=&quot;Beautiful, messy data. Presentation by The Office Of Creative Research.&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/06/Beauty_in_messy_data_with_o-c-r.org_.__sfpc_school.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Beautiful, messy data–presentation by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://o-c-r.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Office Of Creative Research&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s next? More SFPC picnics, I hope! And more Python for me. I’ve been polling my friends in urban policy and historical research for data sets to play with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Sfpc picnic begins. Fort greene park between the tower and tennis court. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sfpc_school&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@sfpc_school&lt;/a&gt; reunion. &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/GhZf4HdVCh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/GhZf4HdVCh&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    — Taeyoon Choi (@tchoi8) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tchoi8/statuses/475732697151995904&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;June 8, 2014&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
  An exciting side note: we did our thing where &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rancid_%28band%29&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rancid&lt;/a&gt; did its thing. Check out this music video shot in &lt;a href=&quot;http://fredbenenson.com/blog/2014/01/19/digital-forensics-rancid-reas-kickstarter-hq/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the very room&lt;/a&gt; where we made 1 bit computers and rained 3D squirrel in virtual space. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://orbitalnyc.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Orbital&lt;/a&gt; for hosting us!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoContainer&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;## &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;birds-of-a-feather&quot;&gt;Birds of A Feather&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SFPC is going through something of an ugly duckling phase itself. Amid &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/3016708/fast-feed/be-a-hacker-or-just-look-like-one-programming-education-promises-a-ticket-to-six-f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the many programming intensives&lt;/a&gt;, SFPC is the odd one that thinks &lt;a href=&quot;http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/08/12/code-to-joy-the-school-for-poetic-computation-opens/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;poets have all the answers&lt;/a&gt; and that &lt;a href=&quot;http://thecreatorsproject.vice.com/blog/school-for-poetic-computation-creative-coding-zach-lieberman-taeyoon-choi-jen-lowe&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hireability isn’t necessarily a sign of success&lt;/a&gt; for a technologist. It dreams of having a flock of its own, a collection of artist schools where we can go from one affordable intensive to another learning what most go to grad school for but with more joy and less overhead. What will creative technology education be like when SFPC finds its flock of swans?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sfpc.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sign up for SFPC’s email list&lt;/a&gt; on the website to hear about upcoming sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/06/school-poetic-computation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/06/school-poetic-computation/</guid>
        
        <category>Reflections</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wanderlust&amp;#8217;s Foiled Goodbye to the Borscht Belt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Live tech demos are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/09/12/apple-demo-fails_n_1871383.html &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;notoriously&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techradar.com/us/news/world-of-tech/10-tech-demos-that-went-horribly-wrong-686352&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;dangerous&lt;/a&gt;. Something inexplicable always goes wrong. &lt;a href=&quot;http://wanderlustprojects.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wanderlust Projects&lt;/a&gt; is subject to this phenomenon, too. No matter how much we scout a location, no matter how carefully we plan, something unanticipated and nerve-wracking happens the day of the actual production. With the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wanderlustprojects.com/candyland&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Candyland Trespass Safari&lt;/a&gt;, we spotted security in the defunct factory for the first time only after our 50 guests had fanned out across the facility. Before the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wanderlustprojects.com/couplesretreat&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Illicit Couple’s Retreat&lt;/a&gt;, one set of joyriders after another pulled over to nose around the property as we were setting up. Luck had been with us though. My collaborator N.D. Austin and I always managed to pull it off in the end. I’m sad to say that luck left us recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found out about the fate of the last of the grand Borscht Belt resorts in December. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kutsher%27s_Hotel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kutcher’s Country Club&lt;/a&gt; will be razed to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.recordonline.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20131129/NEWS/311290331/-1/rss01&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;make way for a yoga retreat&lt;/a&gt;. We visited and were captivated by the sprawling, outdated complex: the massive gathering spaces, the kitschy carpeting, the suits left as if room service had been through just yesterday. Kutcher’s felt like something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;14-01-26TheMamboScout042cc&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/05/14-01-26TheMamboScout042cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;14-01-26TheMamboScout082cc&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/05/14-01-26TheMamboScout082cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3561&quot; alt=&quot;14-01-26TheMamboScout019cc&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/05/14-01-26TheMamboScout019cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3566&quot; alt=&quot;14-01-26TheMamboScout085cc&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/05/14-01-26TheMamboScout085cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I grew up just on the other side of the Hudson River, I had no personal relationship with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Borscht_belt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Borscht Belt&lt;/a&gt;, a collection of 1,000 bungalows and resorts that catered to Jewish New Yorkers from the 1920s through the end of the 20th century. We had to do some research to make sense of Kutcher’s. Borscht Belt lore is a treasure trove of memories. People had good times there that they recount in numerous &lt;a href=&quot;http://catskills.brown.edu/story.shtml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;books and news reports&lt;/a&gt;. I was knee deep in library books on the “Jewish Alps” when I found a haunting video on YouTube. A man explored the dark and vacant Kutcher’s just before the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.recordonline.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20140206/BIZ/402060309&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;estate auction&lt;/a&gt; recording nearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MNIPDoYgeX4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a half hour&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t2muPPWx558&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;of POV footage&lt;/a&gt;, narrating aloud about the memories each spot brought up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I used to go swimming here plenty of times. And the Deep End Lounge… Beautiful chandelier… And now for the first time ever, I’m gonna go into the offices. As you see, the bingo cards which we’d play with Tom and Barry. Yea, good old Tom and Barry Bingo… [&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MNIPDoYgeX4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;video 1 of 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;amp;v=MNIPDoYgeX4#t=282&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;4:42&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yup, and the card room is right over here, just as I thought. Some chairs from the night club. I guess this is where they moved the shul… Don’t ask me why I am doing this. (He picks up the ripped out phone handset off the floor and places it back on the hook.) [&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t2muPPWx558&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;video 2 of 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;amp;v=t2muPPWx558#t=323&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;5:23&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Alright, let’s go back down to the lobby. Back down to the auction. Still so sad… It’s just falling apart. Breaks my heart to see what’s happened in such a short period of time. [&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t2muPPWx558&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;video 2 of 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;amp;v=t2muPPWx558#t=418&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;6:58&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is that sound of sniffles him crying?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wanderlust Projects designed an experience (codenamed “The Mambo”) based on the resort’s heyday. We signed on bands, comedians, a bartender, and even a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/04/16/nyregion/lou-goldstein-borscht-belt-comedian-dies-at-90.html?_r=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tummler&lt;/a&gt;. The two dozen guests were ready to bring their children for a day in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite scheduling the experience on Easter and Passover weekend, the property was suddenly crawling with demolition crew. It was impossible to sneak our sizable group onto the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We left the city behind and headed north on I-87, intermittently chatting and dozing. An hour went by before we pulled over into the parking lot of a rest stop. Benedetto hopped out of the van and asked everyone to gather for a quick pow wow.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[Benedetto] had just received a call from Austin, she said, and it turned out bulldozers and construction workers had beaten us to the event location. Today’s adventure would have to be rerouted. The guests, who just had arrived at Grand Central with even fewer details than I had, were being sent home. She looked genuinely distraught.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/05/21/heres-what-happens-when-n_n_5319604.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Huffington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We managed a solid save for the crew, who were already en rout. Some of the band members said that if we hadn’t said anything, they would have thought that the detour to the Widow Jane Mine was the plan all along. We unfortunately had to disband the guest before they set out on the road. We mailed each family or couple a care package with a personal letter explaining what happened and memorabilia from the resort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2014/05/IMG_9268web.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3567&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_9268web&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/05/IMG_9268web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2014/05/IMG_9289web.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3568&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_9289web&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014/05/IMG_9289web.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sad that our plans to offer Kutcher’s a final farewell were foiled. I was so steeped in the complex emotions the place stirred up for people who visited and worked there that I began to feel those sentiments, or at least some shadow of them, myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gothamist gave us the opportunity &lt;a href=&quot;http://gothamist.com/2014/05/21/kutshers_photos.php#photo-1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;to write about Kutcher’s&lt;/a&gt;. We shared the insights of our research with enthusiasm and appreciation for the larger cultural impact the Borscht Belt had American culture. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://gothamist.com/2014/05/21/kutshers_photos.php#dsq-2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;heartfelt comments on the post&lt;/a&gt; have been a delight to read. Here are a few of my favorites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sent this to my Mom. She says, referring to her late father:&lt;br /&gt;
“i guess that says it all. end of an era. the last time i was at Kutshers with Saba there was a fight between 2 rabbis at the saturday service and Saba won the raffle and got the weekend for free. a fitting end.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I waitressed at the coffee shop there in the early 90s. A guy I dated in college is from the area and we used to drive down and work crazy hours a couple of weekends a month. We stayed in the employee quarters that are hidden away behind the hotel. It really was like Dirty Dancing. Except for the dirty dancing part.&lt;br /&gt;
I have a fond memory of serving coffee to polka legend Jimmy Sturr. He was wearing a purple lamé shirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dad’s Catskills memories were from the early days. He &amp;amp; his parents were musicians, who played in the house orchestras in the 1920s and 30s. One of his earliest memories was of driving up to Joe Slutsky’s Nevele Mansion c. 1925, as a small child. He played in Catskills hotels in the 1930s, when he was a student at Juilliard. He remembered being at some hotel in 1936 or 37, when Naftule Brandwein came to play. After the show, the whole orchestra went into Monty, they go to the deli, and Brandwein starts to play. All over town, windows pop open, and cries echo of “Naftule’s back! Naftule’s back!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the memories, Kutcher’s.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/06/wanderlust-borscht-belt-kutchers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://uncommonplaces.com/2014/06/wanderlust-borscht-belt-kutchers/</guid>
        
        <category>Reflections</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
